<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Food Menu</string>
    <string name="title_fooditem_detail">Cuisine Details</string>
    <string name="ingredient">Ingredient</string>
    <string name="receipe">Receipe</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main">Food Menu</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="button_name">Menu</string>
    <string name="welcome_note">Welcome to South Indian Cuisine</string>
    <string name="dot">.</string>

    <integer-array name="item_ids">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>8</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>10</item>
    </integer-array>

    <string-array name="item_names">
        <item>Onion Uttapam</item>
        <item>Dosa</item>
        <item>Vada</item>
        <item>Idli</item>
        <item>Bajji</item>
        <item>Pulihora</item>
        <item>Lemon Rice</item>
        <item>Uppma</item>
        <item>Kulchha</item>
        <item>Veg Pulav</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="item_prices">
        <item>$10.5</item>
        <item>$10</item>
        <item>$4.5</item>
        <item>$3.5</item>
        <item>$7</item>
        <item>$5</item>
        <item>$5</item>
        <item>$4</item>
        <item>$7.5</item>
        <item>$10</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="item_shortDesc">
        <item> Onion puttam  is a combination of dosa (rice batter Served) with coconut chutney and sambar</item>
        <item> A famous food of South India. Dosa (rice batter) cooked finely and served with chutney and aloo sabzi.</item>
        <item> Vada is the most delicious early morning breakfast in South India, served with chutney.</item>
        <item> Idli is again one popular breakfast which is served with chutney.</item>
        <item> Bajji is more spicy which is made of dal batter and chillis.</item>
        <item> Pulihora is more tasty where rice is mixed with puliyograe.</item>
        <item> Lemon seasoning with rice and pickle.</item>
        <item> Upma is made of rava with some vegetables.</item>
        <item> Kulcha is one again like chapathi served with vegetable samabar.</item>
        <item> Vegetable pulao makes a nice evening meal. Rice and vegeatbles with amazing spces in it</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="item_ingredients">
        <item>Rice batter, potatoes, oil, onion, ginger, garlic, chilli powder,turmeric powder, cumin seeds ,salt, coocnut grinder,vegetables</item>
        <item> potatoes, onions, green chillis, ginger-garlic paste,Rice batter, turmeric powder, red chilli powder, sugar ,salt, butter, coriander, oil,coconut grinder, curry leaves</item>
        <item>Vada:Flour ,Oil , Salt Sour Water: Water, Salt ,Cumin seed,Red chilli powder, Dry ginger ,Sugar, curd, corainder leaves, vegetables</item>
        <item>Refined Idli flour, Baking soda, Butter, Salt, Oil,Onion , Whole white cumin , Turmeric powder, Mustard seeds, Whole coriander, Green chilies , Fresh coriander , Salt, coconut grinder</item>
        <item>All purpose flour, oil , baking soda, salt, ginger-garlic, chilli powder, garam masala, sugar, salt, coriander</item>
        <item>Rice, groudnut ,curry leaves, oil, Salt, pulihora mix powder, jeera, turmeric powder </item>
        <item>Lemon juice , Green chillies, Coriander leaves, green chilli flakes, Oil, Salt , cooked , jeerz,rai, groundnut </item>
        <item> Bansi rava, carrots, green beans, onion, green bell pepper, garlic, ginger, tomatoes, turmeric powder, coriander powder,green chilli powder, oil, salt</item>
        <item>Wheat flour, chillie, vegetables, oil, salt , curry leaves, cumin seeds, rai,onions </item>
        <item>Basmati rice, Black cardamom, Green cardamom, Cinnamon, Garlic , Whole hot spices, Mixed vegetables, Salt, White cumin seed powder, Peppercorns, Onion, Oil</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="item_cookingStyle">
        <item>
            "For the Onion Uttapam:\n\n1.Prepare rice batter, where rice should be overnight soaked it.
            \n2.Heat the oil in a pan, add the pour the dosa batter on it. When dosa is about to be done,add the onion  and sauté till the onion is golden brown.
            \n3.Grind the coconut and chilli with ginger, green chilli, tamrind, garlic and with little water
            \n4.Add the chutney to pan and 1 cup of water and mix well. Simmer for 10 to 15 minutes.

            \nOnion Uttapam
            \n5.Onion uttapam with chutney is ready to serve
            \n6.In small bowl add chuney and one Uttapaam decorate with some carrota and onions"
        </item>

        <item>
            "For Dosa: \n1. Put urad dal and fenugreek seeds in a small bowl, rinse well and add cold water to cover. Leave both to soak for 4 to 6 hours.
            \n2. Drain rice and dal-fenugreek mixture in separate colanders. Put rice in a food processor, blender or wet-dry grinder.grind to a smooth paste
            \n3. Combine the two pastes in a medium mixing bowl.Batter will keep for up to a week, refrigerated. Thin with water if necessary before proceeding
            \n4. Make the potato filling: Put ghee in a wide skillet over medium heat. When oil is wavy, add mustard seeds and cumin seeds.Add turmeric, asafetida, ginger, curry leaves, garlic and green chile. Stir to coat.
            \n5. Mash potatoes a bit with the back of a wooden spoon. Season well with salt, add cilantro, then set aside at room temperature.
            \n6. Flatten the potato mixture slightly. Using the spatula, fold the sides of the dosa around the filling to make a cylindrical shape. Serve immediately"
        </item>

        <item>
            "For Vada \n\n1.Soak Urad Daal for minimum of 4-6 hrs.
            \n2.Drain off all of the water and grind daal in a blender using very little water..
            \n3.Remove batter into a bowl and add Salt, Ginger, Green Chilies, Black Pepper and Asafoetida.

            \nFor Sour water:
            \n4.Whip the batter with a spoon to make it light and fluffy.
            \n5.To make the vadas, wet you hand and scoop up a small portion of batter in your hand.
            \n6.Allow vada to get medium golden brown in oil on one side before flipping over to the other side"
            \n7.Serve hot with chutney or sambar"
        </item>

        <item>
            "For Idli: 1.Grind the soaked rice,Grind the soaked urad dal,Mix the ground rice and urad dal together.
            \n2.Grease the idly plates. If needed sprinkle little water, the batter should be of thick pouring consistency. Pour batter in the molds.
            \n3.When the water begins to bubble up rapidly, place the idly stand in the steamer. Steam it for 10 minutes.
            \n4.Loosen the idly from the plates with the help of a spoon and remove them to a plate. Add some ghee
            \n5.serve with coriander coconut chutney or peanut chutney.
            \n6.Serve hot with chili garlic sauce or chuttni."
        </item>

        <item>
            "1.Slit open peppers and deseed it, bring lots of water to a boil.
            \n2.Take all the ingredients except peppers and oil in a bowl.
            \n3.Add water slowly and make it into a thick batter. The batter shoudn't be too thick.
            \n4.Heat oil for deep frying.
            \n5.Now dip the pepper in batter, fill the inside of the pepper with batter.
            \n6.Drop pepper in and fry till golden.
            \n7.Drain it in paper towel."
</item>
        <item>
            "1.Sprinkle turmeric pwd, salt, a tbsp of oil and few fresh curry leaves.
            \n2.Heat the remaining oil in a cooking vessel, add the mustard seeds and let them splutter. Add dry red chillis, cumin seeds, channa dal, urad dal and fry for a minute till light brown.
            \n3.Add the tamarind extract and jaggery and cook till the raw smell of tamarind disappears, approx 5-7 mts.
            \n4.Serve with appadam/chips, majjiga mirapakaayalu (sun dried chillis) and yogurt. Makes a complete meal."
        </item>

        <item>
            "1.Gently roast and then coarsely powder the coriander seeds. Keep aside.
            \n2.Fry till the spluttering stops and add the ginger and peanuts
            \n3.Fry for another minute. Add the turmeric powder and turn off the fire.
            \n4.Add the lemon juice and mix well..
            \n5.Spread the potato mixture on it.
            \n6.Add the rice, roasted coriander powder and salt to taste and mix thoroughly.
            \n7.Serve with a Raita and Poppadums."
        </item>

        <item>
            "1.Mix well while adding rava in boiling water.
            \n2.Cover the lid of pan and cook rava upma for 5 minutes until all the water evaporates.
            \n3.Once the water is gone, the rava upma is ready to serve.
            \n4.Serve South Indian Rava Upma recipe for breakfast along with a cup of tea or glass of juice."
        </item>

        <item>
            "1.mix all the dry ingredients, flour, baking powder, baking soda, salt, and sugar, and sieve the flour to make sure even mixing
            \n2.Add oil and yogurt to the flour and mix it well, add milk as needed to make soft dough
            \n3.Cover the dough and let it sit for about 2 hours
            \n4. roll them into patties,rolling pin or rolling surface dust little more dry flour
            \n5.Skillet should be moderately hot. Wipe the skillet with few drops of oil.
            \n6.Sprinkle few nigella seeds and little cilantro over the kulcha while kulcha is still wet, and press it with the spatula
            \n7.When the kulcha start to change color and start bubbling flip it over. There will be some golden brown spots
            \n8.Kulcha should have golden brown spots from both sides.Kulcha should not be cooked on high heat otherwise it will not cook through.
            \n9.Kulcha is ready, butter the kulcha before serving."
        </item>

        <item>
            "\n1.Wash the rice twice in fresh water.
            \n2.Leave to soak for 5 minutes, then drain.
            \n3.Warm the ghee in a saucepan, add rice and fry, stirring frequently, for 5 minutes.
            \n4.Add the water and salt, stir and cook till 3/4 of the water has dried.
            \n5.Place saucepan in a moderate oven on a low heat and cook till water has gone and rice is tender."
        </item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
